

## Md. Rohul Amin

## Software Engineer

Sha 66/3, Shadhinata Sarani, North Badda, Gulshan, Dhaka, Bangladesh 🛗 05 Jan 1996

🟲 Bangladeshi 🕲 Unmarried in radipu 🕜 radipu 🖹 radipu 🔇 dipuxoo Bē radipu

radipu.me 🖒 radipu

### **CAREER OBJECTIVES**

I am a graduate with a bachelor's degree in Computer Science and Engineering. I am experienced in both front-end and back-end programming languages. Now, I am looking for establishing my career as a .NET developer. I am a quick learner and willing to learn new technologies to upgrade myself with time. I am working with .NET technology since 2018.

## **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

Jan 2022 Software Engineer
Dhaka, Bangladesh CureTech Ltd

Aug 2021 - Jan 2022Software EngineerSunderland, EnglandGinilab Limited ☑

Ginilab is a software development company based in Sunderland, Tyne & Wear, UK. Over the last few years, they've made a reputation for building software that looks great and is easy to use. Currently, I worked there with .NET Framework, DevExpress, WinForms, Software Design, Fronend, and Back-end.

Feb 2021 – Jul 2021 Software Engineer

Dhaka, Bangladesh OurEdu

OurEdu provides web-based software for educational institutions. I have had working here with C# ASP.NET Core 3.1, JavaScript, Bootstrap, jQuery, LINQ, CSS, MSSQL, DevOps.

PROJECTS

Feb 2022 - present Bachao ☑

Against the rape

It's a mobile application platform where a victim can seek help during and after the incident. The backend was developed with .NET. Technology Used: .NET5, Angular, WebAPI, MSSQL

#### Aug 2021 – Jan 2022 **Rest**

#### **Restaurant Management System**

It's a desktop software, mostly used in the UK and in the middle east. Nearly 200+ restaurants and thousands of customers use this software for ordering food inside and outside the restaurant.

Technology Used: ASP.NET, DevExpress, WinForms, MySQL, Laragon, HeidiSQL

## Feb 2021 - May 2021

# Account Management System for Shidlai Ashraf Secondary School

Technology Used: C#, ASP.NET Core 3.1, JavaScript, Bootstrap, CSS, jQuery, JSON, LINQ, and following by Onion Architecture.

#### May 2019 - Aug 2019

#### Library Management System

Technology Used: C#, ASP.NET Core 2.1, Bootstrap, CSS, jQuery, JSON, LINQ.

#### Apr 2022 - May 2022

#### Faria Nur 🛮

#### Fashion Website

We always wanted to create a label that represents fashion and affordability. Our designs are inspired by top designer houses in India, Pakistan, the UK, and the USA but we render their quality at affordable prices.

Technology used: Laravel, Bootstrap, CSS, JavaScript, MySQL

#### Feb 2022 - present

#### Taja Bajar 🛮

Mobile and Web Application for daily grocery shopping in Bangladesh.

Technology Used: PHP, Laravel, Blade, Bootstrap, JavaScript, CSS, Software Engineering

#### Jan 2022 - Feb 2022

#### **EZCar**

Technology Used: PHP, Blade, Laravel, Bootstrap, MySQL.

## SKILLS

**DevOps** 

**Programming** Language C, C++, Java, JavaScript, C#, R, Python, TypeScript, Go **Backend** Development

.NET Core, .NET, NodeJS, Laravel

AWS, GCP, Azure, Docker, Jenkins, Kubernetes, Bash

Data Structure and -**Algorithm** 

**Cyber Security** Penetration, Forensics, Reverse Engineering, Social Engineering

Frontend

**Development** 

VueJS, Angular, HTML5, AngularJS, Bootstrap3, 4, CSS3, Sass

**Database** 

Oracle, MySQL, MSSQL Server, PostgreSQL

Source Control

Git. GitHub

Interpersonal skills —

Listening, Caring, Leadership, Self-Motivated, Responsibility, Teamwork

## **EDUCATION**

May 2021 Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Engineering

International University of Business Agriculture and Technology Dhaka, Bangladesh

Completed BSc with a CGPA of 3.27 out of 4.00

Jul 2011 - Aug 2013 **Higher Secondary Certificate** 

Dhaka, Bangladesh Cambrian College

Completed HSC with a GPA of 5.00 out of 5.00

Secondary School Certificate Jan 2009 - May 2011 Cumilla, Bangladesh Shidlai Ashraf Secondary School

Completed SSC with a GPA of 5.00 out of 5.00

**INTERESTS** 

 Learning New Skills Public Speaking Reading

Writing

LANGUAGES

**English** Bangla